Curriculum Vitae

Felipe Morales Carbonell

Contact

Isabel Riquelme Sur 1769, dpto. 43 Maipu, Santiago, RM, Chile ef.em.carbonell@gmail.com +32474223578

Short biography

I am a PhD student at KU Leuven, currently working on issues in modal epistemology. My research project aims to give an account of the structure of modal knowledge and of knowledge of so-called agentive modalities and abilities, with the background of knowledge of counterfactuals.

Area of Specialization: Modal Epistemology

Areas of Competence: Epistemology (Formal and Mainstream), Metaphysics, Metaphilosophy,

Philosophical Logic, Wittgenstein's philosophy

Areas of Interest: Aesthetics, Ancient skepticism, Philosophy of Mathematics

Supervisor: Guido Vallejos.

Education

2017-2021	PhD, KU Leuven, Belgium. Project: <i>The Epistemology of Counterfactuals and Modality</i> . Thesis: <i>Agentive Modality and the Structure of Modal Thought</i> . Supervisor: Dr. Jan Heylen. Defended 5/1/2021. Examination committee: Grant Ramsey, Lorenz Demey, Sonia Roca-Royes (external, U. Of Stirling).
2015-2016	MPhil, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium. Thesis: A Model of Understanding: An Account of its Structure and Measures. Supervisor: Dr. Jan Heylen. magna cum laude.
2009-2013	Masters in Philosophy, with specialization in Epistemology, Universidad de Chile, Chile. Thesis: El Problema Epistemológico de los Juicios de Posibilidad como Problema Metafilosófico y sobre el Entendimiento (eng: The Epistemological Problem of Possibility Judgements as a Metaphilosophical Problem and on Understanding"). Supervisor: Dr. Rodrigo González Fernández.
2005-2008	Bachelors in Philosophy, Universidad de Chile, Chile. Thesis: <i>Análisis y Ontología</i> (eng: "Analisys and Ontology").

Scholarships

Beca Chile para estudios de Doctorado en el Extranjero (eng: Chile Scholarship for Foreign Doctoral Studies), CONICYT, Chile.
Beca Chile para estudios de Magister en el Extranjero (eng: Chile Scholarship for Foreign Masters Studies), CONICYT, Chile.
"Game Counterpossibles", Argumenta. 6(1), 117–133, doi: 10.14275/2465-2334/202011.mor
"Epistemic Projects, Indispensability and the Structure of Modal Thought", <i>Res Philosophica</i> , 97(4), 611–638, doi: 10.11612/resphil.1946
"Mistakes as Revealing and as Manifestations of Competence", <i>Synthese</i> , doi: 10.1007/s11229-019-02281-y
"What is the Locus of Abilities?", Rivista Italiana di Filosofia del Linguaggio, Special issue on "Wittgenstein: language, practical knowledge and embodiment" (guest editor: Annalisa Coliva), 12(2), 19-30, doi: 10.4396/20180201
"On the Question of the Indispensability of Modal Thought", in <i>Proceedings of the IX Conference of the Spanish Society of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science</i> , ISBN: 978-84-09-06054-2
"Posibilidades más allá de los fenómenos" (eng: "Possibilities beyond phenomena") in <i>El pensamiento de Kant en la actualidad - Comunicaciones del I Congreso Internacional Kant y el Criticismo: pasado, presente, ¿futuro?</i> (eds. Daniela Alegría, Paula Órdenes), Editora FI, Porto Alegre.
"La malla conceptual de sentido común sobre la conciencia" (eng: "The common sense conceptual network about consciousness"). <i>Anuario de Postgrado 2011</i> , Facultad de Filosofía y Humanidades, Universidad de Chile.
"Sobre posibilidades contingentes" (eng: "On contingent possibilities"), in <i>Metafísica: cinco ensayos de Filosofía Analítica</i> , Publicaciones Especiales del Departamento de Filosofía, Universidad de Chile.
"Counterpossibles in games and Subject Matters for Counterpossibles", CLPS Seminar, Leuven, Belgium.
"Subject Matters for Counterpossibles" <i>ECAP 10</i> , Utrecht, Netherlands (online).
"Imagined, supposed and impossible ways" + "Counterfactual knowability, once again" (with Jan Heylen), XX Jornadas Rolando Chuaqui Kettlun, August 27-30 2019, Santiago, Chile.

2019, July	"What about the bees? Generality and holism in geometry and modality", Open Session of the <i>Joint Session</i> , July 19-21 2019, Durham.
	"Musical attentiveness' modal aspect", <i>The 7th biennial conference of the Music and Philosophy Study Group</i> , Themed Session: A Musical Matter of Mind, July 11–12 2019, King's College, London.
2019, May	"Modality and circularity", <i>Modal Metaphysics: Issues on the (Im)possible VII</i> , May 30-31, Bratislava. Also acted as commentator for Nathan Wildman's (TiLPS) "Necessity by Accident".
	"Imagined and supposed ways", Learning from Imagination, May 23-24, Leeds.
2018, November	"On the question of the indispensability of modal thought", IX Conference of the Spanish Society for Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science, Madrid, Spain.
2018, October	"Accounting for the structure of modal knowledge", <i>CLPS Seminar</i> (doctoral presentation), Leuven, Belgium.
2018, September	"On the global embedding problem for modal expressivism", Salzburg Conference for Young Analytic Philosophy 2018, Salzburg, Austria.
2018, June	"(Non) assertion and modality: from Pyrrho to some contemporary debates", <i>CLPS-DWMC Symposium</i> , Leuven, Belgium.
2018, January	"On the indispensability of modal thought", First Leuven-Paris Analytic Philosophy Workshop: Epistemology, Leuven, Belgium.
2017, September	"Boundaries for Williamsonian epistemologies of modality", <i>CLAW-CEFISES Workshop</i> , Leuven, Belgium.
2017, July	"Knowing (how I can) and counterfactual success", Varieties of Knowing How Workshop, University of Duisburg-Essen, Essen, Germany.
2017, April	"Knowing what is possible atemporally and at all times", 7th Annual Graduate Student Conference, HIW KU Leuven, Belgium.
2016, July	"Attributions of misunderstanding and the context-sensitivity of understanding", European Epistemology Network Conference 2016, Paris, France.
2016, April	"The structure of understanding and its measures", 6th Annual Graduate Student Conference, HIW KU Leuven, Belgium.
2014	"Posibilidades más allá de los fenómenos" (eng: "Possibilities beyond phenomena"), <i>I Congreso Internacional Kant y el Criticismo: Presente, pasado, ¿futuro?</i> , Santiago, Chile.
2013	"Experimentos mentales, comprensión y la tesis de la pluralidad lógica", (eng: "Thought experiments, understanding and the thesis of logical pluralism") XIV Jornadas Rolando Chuaqui Kettlun, Universidad de Concepción, Chile.
	"Descartes y la relación entre la concebibilidad y la afirmabilidad de lo posible." (eng: "Descartes and the link between conceivability and assertability of what is

possible") III Congreso Nacional de Filosofía, Universidad de Valparaíso, Chile.

"Entendimiento y juicios de posibilidad", (eng: "Understanding and possiblity judgement") *IV Coloquio Lenguaje y Cognición*, Universidad de Concepción, Chile.

2011 "¿Se apunta a la verdad cuando se afirman juicios de posibilidad?". (eng: "Do

we aim at truth when asserting possibility judgements?") II Congreso Nacional

de Filosofía, Universidad de Concepción, Concepción, Chile.

2011 "Metafilosofías escépticas a la Wittgenstein y a la Moore". (eng: "Skeptical

metaphilosophies in the style of Wittgenstein and Moore") Coloquio de Estudiantes de Filosofia Analítica, Universidad Católica de Valparaiso, Valparaíso,

Chile

2010 "Sobre cierta resistencia de la imaginación" (eng: "On a certain resistance of

imagination") Congreso Bicentenario, Universidad de Chile, Santiago, Chile.

2008 "Sobre el fallo de los experimentos mentales" (eng: "On the failure of thought

experiments") I Congreso Nacional de Filosofía, Santiago, Chile.

Miscellaneous Publications

2019 "Daydreaming, Philosophy, and the Logics of the Imagination", at *The Junkyard* (scholarly blog on the Imagination). https://junkyardofthemind.com/blog/

2019/12/7/daydreaming-philosophy-and-the-logics-of-the-imagination

Editing/Translation

Various Authors, Metafísica: cinco ensayos de Filosofía Analítica (eng: Meta-

physics: Five Essays of Analytic Philosophy). Publicaciones Especiales del Departamento de Filosofía nº 119, Serie Cursos y Seminarios, Universidad de Chile.

Co-edited with Manuel Rodriguez.

Various Authors, Experimentación Mental (eng: Thought Experimentation) Pub-

licaciones especiales del Departamento de Filosofia nº 118, Documentos del Grupo Cognición y Praxis vol. 40. Co-edited and translated with Rodrigo

González.

Teaching Experience

2018-2019 TA Epistemology (Bachelors level) Institute of Philosophy, KU Leuven.

2019-2020 TA Logic (Bachelors level) Institute of Philosophy, KU Leuven.